it's called zero day attack the main
target that they had historically in
blockchain was e two days ago they
started to infect the system they put a
program in uh in in Google Chrome I am
not proposing people to use uh to use
Chrome actually don't put any web
extension by bit came from cookies
cookies on Google Chrome on your web
browser uh you have extension web
extension usually you can use many type
of extension like translator or whatever
this is the main failure of your
computer but if this extension is
vulnerable if it's a bad application
this application will have access to all
your computer the camera what you type
on your keyboard if you have access your
your bank account if you have access
your uh exchange do they all have all
the informations already is it too late
the hack itself happen in 2 minutes as
much thing you have to protect as more
more vulnerability you have can Hardware
wallets company actually access people's
fun the only thing you should check if
you want to use um a central
change world
going the queen of the game stacking
crypto like it's
[Music]
her hi Jackie hi bunny nice to meet
you nice to meet you too um you are the
cyber security expert and I want to know
how does a person get into this space
because it sounds so cool okay so great
Yes actually it's very cool it's very
interesting it's always interested me in
my life um you start with U I suppose
when with a normal uh engineer computer
uh School uh like I did and you get into
it with uh uh if you study cryptography
if you study some like deep mathematics
uh stuff into your uh study life but
after that um on my career I became an
architect so I am an architect engineer
it engineer so I provide a solution and
architecture and advice to update
upgrade and secure a global architecture
for very big company over the world this
is my job and in my career I um I got
more and more uh deeply into uh security
of this of the data and finally I got
involved into cyber defense so uh I am
now um proposing my services of uh
advising on which technology to to to
adopt and to adapt into an existing uh
um environment to secure very high and
sensible data so this is what I do in my
job in cyber security in the Cyber
defense um government in France oh you
work for the government too it's um
always you know when we are talking
about defense uh it's always related to
the government I am not working for the
government but it's of course defense
area is related to uh to government
somehow I am not working for the
government if you understood So when you
say yeah I get I get it except for
defense right you also do cold wallet
audits uh today I realize audits mainly
for people like you and me final users
of of um
a wallet or a coldw or a software wallet
to help to protect them uh their um
transaction to protect their life there
are critical data there and to protect
like to also to uh explain how to react
how to um how to have a better life uh
in online and to to be protected and not
to make like um strong problem like to
create problems with their um with their
data with their transaction and with
everything they have like I phone or
computer how to react good on this on
every situation uh so that's mainly what
I do and about uh companies about Wess
companies I have um been in contact with
for example a ledger also to talk about
their um kind of uh problems that I I
could find somehow and uh they are
working on many of course subject and
also uh more uh in more uh deep detail
in uh wangm uh wallet that on my side I
found a very high level of security on
their architecture so mainly what I do
is to analyze the architecture of of the
of a wallet and to give my opinion on on
why this aspect of the wallet is not
unsecure but more a vulnerability and
why this aspect is very strong by just
cber by cyber security aspect um so for
example uh I am uh on my side I have um
uh so like I said I am working with the
Cyber defense area industry and uh we
are uh mainly followed in those def in
those industry by a government
governmental entity that is auditing us
because they as um a deep important
entity of influence in the government we
must um be sure that all what we are
doing all the protocols that we are
doing all the applications that we we
put in place are respect respect a
certain level of uh of security so we
are always audited by by by this entity
that's called
ANC security
system mean cyber security um
company for friends and uh um and what I
wanted to say is uh that they provide me
always the best uh certification the
best practices to how to secure and what
what we want to reach so they provide me
some good good advice some good um
example good ideas how to do so when I
apply their advises on of on Wallets on
crypto wallets and Hardware wallets I
can directly identify what is good what
is not good like globally like as an
idea uh that doesn't mean that it's a
critical vulner vulnerability or
critical attacks or danger but it's a
kind of vulnerability or other aspect
can be um a good point a good point for
not being a vulnerability so we will
discuss about that I suppose would you
say like people like Regular People will
think war is between countries like it
involves all the weapons and stuff but
in cyber world a lot of war is ongoing
but people just don't see it when you
open your television what happened like
the war in uh in Ukraine the war like
whatever in even the problem in Middle
East but you have exactly at the same
moment you can follow the cber attacks
of all those area and we can see that
very very important groups um makes a
war in the Cyber def cyber world uh
exactly at the same moment that we have
a real uh war with uh with people you
provide services for like private entity
as well right how do people find you if
they really need your service yeah um so
actually I provide um this activity is a
globally um I conduct it through uh
private groups but now I open myself to
to everyone so again it's for final user
not for a company uh today and people
will find me over my website that I am
now constructing a building uh it's um
crypto uh Crypt security audit.com I I
will provide you this link I will
provide usually now people contact me by
by LinkedIn uh contact me by um by mail
that I provide but I will provide all
those information into my website and I
will provide it to you if you will'll be
able to to add it in comments and to
people let people no perfect because
people need this service it's like hello
we're helpless here we need you you know
yes yes totally uh so yeah I see how
people need the uh this kind of advice
and I make very very deep audit on every
aspect of uh of uh of this uh of your um
of your life a digital life and uh I got
very deep into uh how to protect what
choice you have to make uh on
application on uh on devices and very
Global advice that you have to follow in
your life like everyday life not even
directly related to crypto it's uh how
to to to have a safe uh um Behavior
online that's also that can you tell me
one that you think I would not expect
you have a web browser you you use
Chrome as I understand that's the first
thing I don't I don't I don't agree with
I am not proposing people to use uh to
use Chrome actually I Pro I suggest to
people to use Modzilla Firefox or Brave
that is directly um more into um focused
onto confidentiality and security of
your data instead of Google Chrome of or
solutions that are provided by big
company and that can have access to your
data because it's a governmental law to
let them access to your data if there is
any cber defense any cyber security uh
um um law from the government that that
is found somehow uh into your area or
your system they are by low author
authorized to access your data that's
something yeah so as a fact at this
point I am also auditing this uh GDP
jdpr in France we have we are talking
about um personal data security so I I
have been auditing those the company to
uh to be sure that there are uh
compliance in this gdpr um stuff like
private data privacy data we are talking
about this privacy data law um to come
back on your question on your web
browser uh you have extension web
extension usually you can use many type
of we extension like um translator or
whatever like to put bright or the dark
aspect of your web browser this is the
main failure of your computer like the
real main failure you have to understand
that those extension are addon to your
uh to your program that is mainly secure
let's say even if you use Google Chrome
um but if this extension is vulnerable
if it's a bad application this
application will have access to all your
computer all your computer in the web
browser environment that mean the camera
what you type on your keyboard what you
have access if you have access to your
bank account or if you have access your
uh exchange even if you have multiple uh
authentication um double authentication
or biometrical authentication he will
see everything you do in online like
live on live uh aspect so uh even if you
do all what you want he will have access
to it so my main something that you you
could be you should be aware of is not
to let any web extension be vulnerable
like actually don't put any web
extension if you want to use a software
wallet that is the most critical wallet
uh on the um blockchain ecosystem so use
just this wallet and nothing else like
for example metam mask put just metam
mask or rabi wallet and that's all
nothing else because this is the main
way to be uh to be
hacked so let's say I have the extension
I do right now I want to remove it but I
I'm really worried is it just going to
if they could see me now do they all
have all the information already is it
too late no Al I don't think it's too
late because if it would be the case you
would be already hacked so we we yeah
let's be honest but if you uh uh if you
have still this system you can simply uh
remove uh all your extension and you can
remove your uh um your software wallet
from uh Chrome and to install um Firefox
or Brave and to reinstall your software
wallet in in in folks and everything
will be okay globally let's talk about
the biggest hack of humankind which is
the bybit incident that just happened
um I want you to maybe break it down
from a cyber Security Experts
perspective because from us like for us
we see it on the news and it's analyzed
by God knows who right it's probably not
an expert so from your perspective
what happened what exactly happened what
went wrong okay so first uh when we saw
that uh on the news like you and me uh
we uh wanted to know um who was behind
that and we discovered that it was a
very big uh group it was Lazarus cyber
group cyber attacker from North Korea so
we definitely understood that it was not
a simple hack it was a very prepared and
uh uh very um uh like yeah very
synchronized hack actually the hack
itself happened in two minutes is
globally the yeah it's the timing of a
of of an attack between 30 seconds to
two minutes usually it doesn't take more
than that and in two minutes they did a
60 or 70 transaction of
10,000 eum uh that's what they did in 2
minutes uh so it took really two minutes
but it have been prepared before I mean
uh the hackers um uh already get inside
the system before it happened like two
days ago they started to infect the
system but uh when they infect a system
they inserted um they put a program in
uh in in Google Chrome so I have to say
it it was on the yeah that's what
happened in the Google Chrome web
browser uh of uh of the signature like
on bybit people um they insert this code
to allow to allow the program to
activate to be activated in very certain
circumstances when um with a very
specified wallet and P specified person
owner of this wallet because we are
talking about multi now so let me
explain you how it started um so one day
like in the middle of the week um it was
on 17 like don't really remember because
the hack happened on Friday but two days
ago um Lazarus group inserted uh they
send um a hack into the safe uh wallet
they infected the multi signature uh
system so uh that use that is using uh
bybit so what is happening in bybit when
they made those big moves every day they
have also cold wallet what I provide
like is ex exactly what I would propose
to you use a cold wallet so they big
money are not online they put it online
when they need to make transaction so
they have cold wallet so it's mainly
cold wallet that are uh compatible with
multi signature system so it's uh we are
talking about like type of treasure and
Ledger type of cold wallet and um they
uh they they have their wallet on Multi
signature system so that means that
there is several people that need to
sign the transaction so for from here
everything is normal they do that every
day or every week I don't really know uh
and what happened is that
uh this multi signature came from safe
um safe smart contract so we are talking
about before it was called gnosis safe
gnosis um smart contract multi signature
now we are talking just about safe safe
wallet and they their multi signature
was B on a safe program safe smart
contract so two days ago like I said uh
Lazarus group sent um a hack into the
system into the uh the web interface
into the display system of safe uh
platform that's very interesting and
this is the start of like what of the
shocking of of what happened because
they introduced their hack from the just
the display interface of safe it wasn't
the smart contract that was hacked the
smart contract itself just allow uh
exactly like he would allow any
transaction but the display of safe that
is safe Point Global this is application
that that has been hacked was intro like
received a hack that allow to modify uh
just before signing the transaction it
they it it it allow uh to change the
Destin the the the final address the
global address of the receiver so here
what I want you to understand and to
identify as a fail like as something not
normal is that the display system of
safe allowed to manage the safe like the
the contract side the certification as
um and in fact it should just be
something just to display the system
safe Point Global it's an application
for the web interface just in front we
are talking about something that should
just display information not change any
part of the signature so that was the
first shocking thing that how this
display application could be could
modify the the final destinator but this
is what happened so two days ago they
changed that this um change um got into
action when um they identified first the
wallet they wanted to hack so it's a a
wallet with like with this huge money
and the people they identified also they
have to investigate also who is the
owner of this uh of the those wallets
like who are the multi signatur owner of
this wallet so in the code we can
directly see the list of uh public
address of the owners and the list of
the of the wallets they wanted to hack
and if those wallets are in the
condition so okay we the program is
launched so this is the beginning of the
code and um um also we have to
understand that this system of safe is
uh they you know they have U they deploy
it into a system also like everyone any
website is deployed into a cloud or
whatever and safe and the safe system is
deployed into a WS S3 so it's very
Global that's also a second point I have
to mention when I investigated on the
audit that uh has been um directly um
export like showed by the CEO of bit
himself he did an investigation and this
and and I read directly the report from
the CEO uh that he put on on X directly
so I read it and the conclusion of this
audit is that we are still trying to
understand if the failure if on if the
vulnerability came from Amazon S3 or
from another aspect but this is we have
to say that they had to introduce this
uh this hack into Amazon so somehow they
could have access they could reach the
data authentication to access this rep
three this Amazon server so we can see
that here we have Amazon that is a uh on
one side if they had access to uh to the
correct uh identification
like if they could steal those
identification system to introduce the
system of Amazon or if they hacked
Amazon this I don't know yet but uh the
second point is that there is human here
that is involved this is the main point
I want to to to explain here when uh
usually a system is hacked mainly
statistically it's human that is behind
a problem behind a failure as less human
you have uh more security you have
that's that's a fact uh if you let
yourself to have your own seat fres that
means that you let yourself as a human
trying to to protect or to hide your
your seat fres but somehow somehow
someone could find it so I I am also
part um as as TM um propose part of
proposing not to not to let seed phase
system to uh to recover your data uh
it's something that you have to hold on
your side yeah it's uh the CE of TM said
that it's it's a time bomb and actually
I understand this point of view because
um you have to protect this SE phrase
It's with this SE phrase you can access
all your money so you have to protect it
to protect it as much as your wallet I
mean you have two things to secure now
instead of one of course the seat phrase
is a solution to have a backup yes
that's funny of course yes if you if you
think about it you know cyber security
is very simple it's very simple as much
thing you have to protect as more more
ability you have okay so don't need to
make it more complicated more like don't
create you trouble one system secure it
and that's all okay that's my point of
view and uh that's what TM does actually
um so to come back on on what happened
in bybit we have cold wallet people that
signed a transaction with safe and uh
what is what have been hacked is their
computer is what is uh what was right on
on the computer and on the interface of
safe with so they went on safe they
signed the transaction so the hack
modified the the the address on the on
the screen of their computer on safe so
uh they didn't see anything uh bad on
the screen but on the wallet itself on
the little screen that this little
display on their little wallet the
address was not the correct one it was a
human failure we are directly talking
about blind signing they if they would
have to take one second each of them
they all did the same mistake all the
signers if they would see that the
address on their wallet was not the same
on their screen nothing would happen so
it wasn't a 100% uh um hack uh um
nonvisible hack if they would take this
time to see that what they signed on
their on their cold wallet was not the
same uh address uh that is on the screen
they would recognize that uh there will
be a problem and they would not sign it
so that's my vision on what I know now
maybe maybe there is something new that
will tell me that no even the cold
wallet was hacked but for the moment no
the cold wallet was not hacked it's just
the safe the safe uh display system that
was hacked I think I I watched the um
interview or like the Q&A with Benzel
right after what happened I think what
he was saying is with multi Sig the
screen doesn't really show the full
thing and he probably it probably
couldn't fit the little screen so he
just signed a little screen display on a
little device like like on this side you
know it's not enough it's not it's not a
hardware wallet but usually Hardware
wallet like uh treas or uh or Ledger are
very small and you the display is too
small okay have bigger now bigger wallet
but on this little screen you can't you
can't as you say you can just see some
few uh few part of the characters of the
of the address and you have to wait or
to click on next to see the next part
maybe but it's not enough it's not
enough so they said that if the display
is on the wallet so it's secure like
it's a safe display um in my vision in
my uh analyze it's not if the display is
on the device that proof that it's
secured but actually here on safe it
wasn't the case the display exact really
displayed the correct information so we
are not we will not go into
vulnerability of that it's not the point
here but if the display was bigger we
could directly see that the address is
not it was not good I think that as
human like like you and me we don't want
to to it's very uncomfortable to uh to
see uh things like on one just one
online it's not not easy to to read
something so that's why they trusted
their their device like their computer
on safe and they didn't read anything on
the device that's also a point that I
want to mention so the connection you
have between the display on the hardware
wallet this is the question should be
how the display is connected to your
device um for example on uh on a
hardware wallet like treasure or Ledger
uh it's just a physically um connected
if that means that um if uh someone
could access like open the system and
try to make some Vault injection or
stuff like that you could access the
data you could modify things and access
some information for example on on a
tangent it's just a card and it's just
holding the private key and the public
key nothing else there is no entry
points there is no USB there is nothing
and it's not even upgradeable that it's
something on my side I think that it's a
uh it's it's a good point but of course
we can discuss about this we can't uh of
course somehow sometime we will probably
need to upgrade on to update something
but this is also another subject but the
point is that the the connection between
the card and the display the display is
on the smartphone and what is what
connects you the this the the the smart
the hardware wallet to the display
is a cryptographic certificate that's
that's strong that's really strong if
there is a problem on the smartphone or
if there is a problem on your card like
tangum card so if one of them is not
correct the communic the communication
will will just stop it it won't
recognize because it's based on a
certificate on a cryptographic
certificate just to be sure that you
understand how deep important it is all
the blockchain is bed on on
cryptographic certificate it's the
principle of the blockchain so I that's
why I think that it's much more stronger
way to communicate between uh the wallet
and the screen just in if uh and in
corporation if with a hardware wallet
with a screen inside that you can modify
by opening the box and to create some uh
like when I was saying volt injection
it's when you try to manipulate the
electricity on it and to create trouble
to the device and to generate some wave
electricity wave and to analyze those
wave and to see okay this is a this is B
this is C like exactly something like
that you can have those system to to
hack the system you can have those um
option to hack the
system finally the people on bybit they
just um they just haven't read correctly
it's a human failure first of all human
failure about uh the fact that they
didn't read correctly their the the
address the final address on the wallet
on the hardware wallet and also um this
it was a hack on on from the safe side
because the display system was not
supposed to be able to modify the
transaction itself and this is what
happened so we can have also here uh a
development like application
architecture that was not really correct
the display was not supposed to to do
anything about decisional things like
what uh what address to to uh to to
deploy what address to what is the
correct address and um and that's all so
we have those two parts to identify so
we are talking about blind sing human
comprom Mission and uh software
application compromis on on the safe
side okay well what you just said about
the uh Hardware wallet with a screen I
need to play Double's advocate here
because I've heard other experts saying
that the most important thing for a
hardware wallet is to have a screen now
I'm hearing all different things now and
I want to know your point of view So
when you say okay for example the bit
situation they didn't read it correctly
but let's say today if they were using
tenum then the display will be on the
phone it's an app now the app could be
hacked but what you were saying is if I
used a card and I skin it won't scan yes
it's it's working like that if the
application or the wallet is uh not uh
is not authentic the certificate that is
you know it's a a cryptography
certificate it's like a hash a hash it's
a it's something that you can't modify
if there is one bit one uh um single
information that is changed everything
is is broken like the communication is
broken because the the result of the
check there is a check number uh that
that is very very precise if there is
one little thing that Chang the communic
the this number this big number will
change so uh so the communication will
stop it won't recognize it so that's why
I say that if they would have used uh
the TM wallet and if the application
let's say the application would be
hacked on uh on your smartphone so the
the card will not recognize the system
and you say no I can sign it it's not
it's not the application it's something
else I don't know what it is but it's
not the application
so the card and and it will happen
because the card itself is uh when you
create when you initialize it it's it's
done it's finished there is no there is
no possibility to modify it unless you
want to destruct it like it's just a c
like what what can you do this first of
all the the system that is on this card
is the same system that you use to
validate your your passport when you
change country when you have this
passport control there is a a shipset
inside that is the same chipset on
tangum card uh this ship set actually is
also used in cber defense inference
actually uh so it's a very high secure
system and you can't modify it it just a
card so if there would be any problem
the card would not would not authentify
and in the opposite if the card would
have a problem the application would not
identify the card so it's B directional
and uh what Lazarus group had to do here
uh is to find a way to attack a system
without being here it's totally they did
it from from very far no one was here in
front to to be inside by bit to modify
something inside because of course
that's that's a part of it could happen
like that like someone inside a spy that
would uh open a back door to do
something very fast but it's not like
that this Lazarus group operate in total
distant uh method and like you said has
this big bigger screen the device Flex I
think you think if they were using that
it would be
preventable yes I think it would be
because because as a human uh it
preventable just again it's we're
talking about human if you if you read
correctly what happened you would see
but of course in on a big screen I think
this leg The Ledger that you are talking
about is very big like that so if you
would see correctly the address you
would uh you would see that it's not the
same address on the on the screen and on
your Hardware wallet but of course it's
bigger so you can see it globally so
yes one last question so you said tangum
it won't scan if it was hacked but with
Ledger then that means Ledger has a
different way of transmitting the
information because otherwise you can
say the same about Ledger if it's wrong
it shouldn't go through yes um um and
yes you are right and actually Ledger
did wasn't impacted here the hardware
wallet itself here in bit use case is
not in Fault the hardware wallet showed
the correct false address it showed the
address of the hackers but just a few
part just a few parts I see that's the
point and um that's what that's what
happened I'm just saying that here if
they would have a bigger screen they
could probably see that it's not the
same
but the hardware totally identify the
hacker uh
address okay I see I see yeah that's
what I saw on reports as well it says it
has nothing to do with the hardware
wallet itself but your suggestion is to
have like a bigger string with a bigger
screen which I think it's very fair to
say totally it's just well exactly what
we said if with the bigger screen they
could see that it's not the correct
address as what I know right ha can
actually stay in the system for a while
and wait for the perfect Tim you are
right yeah so that's true so how do I
even know if they're already in my
system like in my phone let's say or in
my laptop you can use all the software
to scan and all that but I don't know
because like really good hacker groups I
feel like they can do anything if they
want to like you said earlier B you I
can't tell you how much right you are
because we are talking here about
something I wanted to share and I forgot
myself we are it's it's a it's called a
zero day attack a zero day attack it's a
day it's it's a a type of attack that is
happening with zero day uh prevention
zero day anticipation that's the def
that's what happened when hackers found
a failure in a system and keep it hidden
hidden keep it uh uh in a secret and
they will use it in a very strategic
moment and that's exactly what happened
with a very very um good group of
hackers like very high uh um skills of
hackers and usually we are talking about
almost governmental entities or hacker
like Lous group that have many it's like
have it's kind of a joker card you know
that they keep for big opportunities and
that's we call that's what we call zero
day attack and to be honest here in
bybit it was a zero day attack from safe
because I'm sure that this this
vulnerability they found it a lot before
but they wanted to find the correct
opportunity the correct timing to hack
and to attack safe on with this system
because they know they knew of course
that when they will make this attack
safe will patch this vulnerability so
they wanted to have the huge the biggest
amount and they did it 1.
14674 billion uh it's it's
huge yeah so yes we are talking about a
zero attack you're right and for okay
like for a normal person retail users we
don't have that big of an amount but
we're still worried about our system
being hacked and we don't realize it
yeah so like and and you said no system
is 100% secure then it become like a
philosophy type of qu question yeah do I
start or do I not or like what do I do
it feels like you're going to be
attacked regardless usually you can be
safe on your side because uh first of
all I'm sure that un andb have zero day
attack on our system there is a zero day
attack maybe on uh I am using a Windows
system you are maybe on Max system but
uh there is probably some zero attack
Ono like some failures secret failure
secret vulnerability but you and me are
not at a governmental level to be reach
by the attack if uh you would be
attacked that's what I told you before
if you would have a vulnerability you
would already been attacked you are not
kind of personality that would uh that
were that an attacker group a hacker
group would wait the correct opportunity
to ACC you are not at this level you are
not by bit we are we are not this kind
of level you we are just uh we are
targeted by
lower hackers that is that are mainly
wait wait for um social engineering H
type of hacking you don't have to worry
about those kind of attacks it's not for
us yeah see that makes me feel better
yeah I feel better for that yeah don't
worry and and um benzo like the B CEO's
interview he said something that made me
think he said he was transferring from
or out of I can't remember warm wallet
now then I looked up like your our
presentation you said there's cold
wallet hot wallet and warm wallet you
put tum under cold Ledger and treas
under war ah uh no I all all of them are
are cold treasure Ledger and tangum are
cold but actually what is true is that
on my conferences I said that tangem is
ex is real cold wallet and I put
actually Ledger and treasure as as um
worm not warm but less cold wallet
because it's just by definition I again
I don't attack here Ledger or treasure
but by definition what is a cold wallet
is a system that hold your private key
and and public key not connected to
Internet that's the definition by
definition cold is not connected you
know cold wallet so stuff you know that
because now you are talking about uh
about crypto but before crypto World in
my in my job we were talking about Cold
Storage it it exists before and cold
storage is just a storage that you have
humanly take the data with the USB key
from here and to walk and to put it in a
Cod like somewhere else it's not
connected to Internet this is cold so
Tang wet is a card it's not doesn't have
any input output just this NFC system to
Output the authorization there is no
connection there is not entry point and
in instead of Ledger and treaser system
that have connections that they have USB
port because it's a system that has to
be upgraded upgradeable they have to
upate they have to update the system
they have to update the ship the ship
set and they have to to to make
communication between the hardware
wallet to your computer to sometimes to
make transaction but even if you you
make the transaction offline but by
definition treaser on Ledger can be
online you can connect it to your
computer so that's my conclusion it's
not totally cold do you understand what
I
mean I see I see okay so um this
question I think a lot of people who are
not in crypto for a long time would be
very curious now when I store funds in a
hardware wallet a lot of people think
you're actually storing it in the device
but it's not tell us where does the
money actually go and how do I make sure
that I am the only person that can
access the fund good question okay so as
you said the fs are on the blockchain
they are decentralized and this is the
key word of everything everyone that own
uh a node everyone that have uh those
you know those um miners that what we
call miners those people who uh have
downloaded all the blockchain or their
computer they own all the
data they have uh the the they are the
proof of uh of the the veracity of the
truth like of the of the real trace of
the of the money so the coins are online
like they are on this decentralized
system everyone have the same register
the same log of U of data because the
blockchain is just a log of transaction
nothing else and this is uh where the
money is it's on the chain on chain and
what you have a hardware wallet is is an
by definition the definition is an
asymmetric cryptographic system
generator that mean what that mean that
your uh asymmetrics mean um asymmetric
cryptographic it's uh private and public
key for example in in difference a
symmetric uh system is just one private
key and you have to share if you and me
Bonnie you would want to share a secret
together you we would have to share the
same private key this is
symmetric we were using that during the
the first and second world war but after
that we started to use second as like
asymmetric system mean a public key and
a private key and then the public can be
public that's the point of it and you
will have a public key to encrypt and I
will have a public key sorry um private
key to encrypt and on my side I will
decrypt so this is how it work so now
the the hardware wallet just hold
private key and public key nothing else
that's the role of the hardware wallet
uh and then uh that's why this uh this
system should not be somehow upgraded or
uh when we are talking about the screen
for example the screen is something we
can understand that can that has to be
upgraded that's have to to have updates
because the phone is being updated and
things like that so if you put the
screen on the wallet you put somehow a v
not somehow you put a vulnerability
because you have to upgrade all the wet
like all the device with the screen and
that's why 10 GM somehow it's it's a
it's a very interesting system a secur
system because the card itself doesn't
have any screen and it holds you your uh
your private key and public key nothing
else and that's the real sense of a
wallet to hold public unprivate
key and you they do it intentionally
right intentionally no screen exactly
intentionally this system has been
raised by the CEO by uh checking all the
fa like failure and all the
vulnerabilities of all other wallet and
he created TM wallet it's like a super
super secure system raised by uh by all
the the the viability of other wallets
earlier you said human failure right
yeah and you want to hold as little
things as possible I think you said
something about um humans should not be
holding their private key or seed phrase
SE phrase seed phrase seed phrase okay
humans should not okay you said humans
should not be able to hold their seed
phrase then where should it go go like
tell us what you mean by that okay um
when you create a hardware wallet you
generate a public and private key yes
this is the system and um usually uh
like SE phrase is a system uh that allow
you to make a backup of your Hardware
wallet if if you need it and um the
system a hardware wallet that is created
with SE phrase actually you don't you
you just not uh generate SE uh private
key and public key those public key and
private key are generated from the seat
phrase so it's a system where this the
private key and public key are generated
from this seed phrase and this is
another system TM created a private key
and public key uh totally without a SE
phrase so it's autogenerated it's not uh
it doesn't generate uh the public and
privative from the SE phrase this is
something I want to tell you and uh from
this you have to understand that if you
generate uh your wallet through uh a SE
phrase so you have you have your
Hardware wallet that you have to secure
and you have the SE phrase here 12 or 24
words that you have to okay where would
I put it like you will start to to uh to
make a ho in your wall like to to to
secure it like what will I do with it
you you think that it's well hidden but
maybe someone saw it some one day and
you will just wake up one day and you
will see that your wallet was uh was
totally uh like is totally empty and you
will finally see that yes maybe this uh
this secret place was not as secret as I
saw that's the point you have to hold
two Secrets your wallet and the seed
phrase two questions that came from what
you just said first question is what if
tangent goes down because with the seed
phrase I can kind of get my fund back
now if I don't have that what do I do
yeah so that's the first question uh so
you see this uh TM has a system with two
or three card or ring and uh if you so
let's say you have three card if you
lose one card and um you you lose even
the second card somehow uh you still
have one card to say okay now it's time
to change wallet you could you will take
the money you of of your last card and
you will uh send it to a new wallet TM
or whatever you want that's the first U
principle of U of TM and you say what
happen if tangent fall what tangent is
the can't the
the let's say the store so actually it's
a very simple simple thing you can the
application is totally
uh disconnected from TM environment it's
on on GitHub it's totally official Place
platform to to have programs you you
just have to go on the link you click
you can install it like exactly like you
would do with your Apple store or um
Samsung store whatever Android store and
you will have it on your phone and you
will totally be able even if tangum
doesn't exist anymore uh you would
totally be able to reach your F and to
communicate with your uh with your
wallet and to be able to transfer it
everywhere you want it will continue to
work second question I thought of when
you just said what um from what you just
said yeah is you said uh private key and
public key is from seed phrase and see I
was totally wrong I thought C phrase was
from private key no you generate the
private key and public key from the SE
phrase yes I see I see okay so with
tenum I don't have seed phrase is that
what you're saying yes 10 G 10 gem can
generate uh public key and a private key
without SE phrase it's not connected to
a SE phrase you can generate by yourself
you know it's a it's a protocol that
exist again since the second world war
and now after that the blockchain has
created to has used this this
cryptographic system to make a new
system that Satoshi Nakamoto created but
whatever we are still talking about
asymmetric uh cryptographic system that
is public and private key so you can
create by itself uh a private private
and public key the only thing is that
sit phrase It's A system that uh you
already have a sentence that means that
you already have uh a root of uh of your
uh of your system and you create um you
generate private and publicy from this
route that means that they are they
depends from it that's how and that's
why you can have a backup from your
wallet with a sitras because those
numbers has been created from it so this
is the system of of of a SE phrase and
you can also like I said generate it
without SE phrase and uh have two
totally new um private and public key
okay um which one would you which way
would you personally pick because I
think a lot of last time I talk about
tenum I think a lot of people raised the
question of okay if I don't have seed pH
isn't that very dangerous U so again
what I I would pick and what I am what I
do actually is to have a system without
switch phrase I trust this system
because I don't want to have this uh uh
uh this complication to to to to to put
this sit Fray somewhere and to to hide
the system I don't like the fact that me
as human have to hold and to secure
system that is already secured by itself
like seriously blockchain is very secure
like uh Bitcoins
cryptographic system is nowadays the
most secure things we have so no need to
to think that your se phras you will
like you will hide it in the wall of
your neighbor and it will be better so I
don't trust those system that's my
choice to be a seedless system big topic
that always come up when it comes to
Hardware wallet is can the company
actually access your funds and I always
hear different companies coming out with
reports and stuff saying that hey us we
cannot but someone else can so I want to
ask you can Hardware wallets company
actually access people's funds to so to
answer directly no they they don't have
this possibility it will be a huge uh
risk from them to to to be to allow this
process because if someone will find it
it will be the catastrophe to be honest
now it seems like all wallets have some
flaws right but I have not here what
could go wrong with
tangum what like I when you when you say
no system is 100%
totally secured right what could go
wrong with tenum like I said the main
vulnerability is entry out uh is entry
point of a system I'm I'm talking even
of Hardware wallet every system the the
main thing you want to know is how to
access it even in the war we are talking
about the Troy War here how they they
could insert uh this this huge castle
they they send like you know the the
horse stoy they insert something inside
the system they got inside so this is
the main question in cyber security how
to connect to be inside the system uh
the on this angle aspect of
consideration uh t uh TM card yes TM
card connection is NFC this is only only
protocol that open to communication and
NFC um system protocol uh it's uh um is
blocked on uh on right like it's there
is no input way but anyway if you would
want to access a tantum card you would
have to face the NFC protocol and to
find a way to interact with the card uh
I really don't know how it could be
possible because the the protocol NFC
protocol is blocked for input is just
for output just to validate the
transaction so far I never heard that
it's uh has been
possible it's what about what about the
Ring The Ring is a same system the ring
is based on uh on an NFC protocol with u
uh with ex exactly the same system with
the same chip set as as far as I
understand with exactly the outputs like
the readable um NFC uh uh firmware so
just to to to make you a little joke
about that if you are able to hack TM so
you will be able to hack your passport
okay so I don't think that the
government will allow that I told you
the ship set is the same that on your
passport it's a it's a passport security
system if you if you sued to H that you
will have problem with
government okay I see I see now I know
that you can stake tokens on tum but my
question will be if the thing is off
offline how do you even do that the
transaction itself is on chain so the
chain is of course is on the on the on
the web like it's online it's just a
process the final process of signature
came we said that it's offline because
the device is not connected to Internet
it's a hard it's a cold wallet it's a
cold system not connected so in the end
of all those online system you take your
signature system your cold wallet
signature system and you connect your
wallet to it so instantly and that's why
it's I I talk about that before um
Ledger and treasur type uh you can put a
cable and connect to your computer and
uh and this is a part of of on my side
part of the problem but you can also not
connect anything and to go on your
device and validate the transaction
because it's somehow uh connected uh to
um uh to your computer to to validate
to synchronize in transaction so it must
be connected somehow you are right it's
not very very clear like very uh easy to
expl to to explain how is totally
offline uh because the transaction
itself is online I mean the yes the
transaction yes the staking but the
signature the validation is offline
because it's on your device just
something that you have on your hand
okay that's uh and and it depends this
final step depends on the device I know
that for tangum uh you you have this
card it's a proof of the system and you
just uh when you tap on your phone it's
I directly understand that it's offline
because the device remain offline on uh
other Hardware wallet uh somehow it has
to be uh it has to be connected to the
system I don't want to to mistake my
understanding of other protocol because
I very deep uh focus on on on on on on
the step on on the protocol to to share
my advice so how to when is exactly the
offline process the offline step of
validation I will still not need to
focus on every system but the signature
globally is offline we want to talk
about Lazarus group
yeah okay Lazarus group fine um oh what
do you know about them lar is group what
do I know about them it's just uh their
reputation and uh that they are involved
into
um it's very they are involved into
financing um North Korea Government
globally there are almost governmental
entity that hack other countries that
are enemies globally of North Korea to
find FS for the government so we are
talking about and I hope I don't say uh
mistakes about that because it's not my
point here I it's just Global Knowledge
that I that I have about them they have
very good skills they are um uh trained
in uh North Korea in sometime not in
North Korea they have very uh good uh
founds like they are they have very good
skills but also very good um environment
to to provide their their it's yeah to
provide to create those attacks uh by
the fact that they it's very organized
very strong uh entities and they can um
their role is just to HCK a very very
huge system with very huge profit it's
uh that's what I can say on the on this
uh on this Lazarus group we we will you
will see their name on bybit and you
will globally they they reach just
targets from starting from 500 Millions
dollars or Euro by F not only on crypto
of course and this is their role to
reach strategic chirurgical attacks on
very huge profit and that's I know what
that's what I know uh about lar group
globally what type of platforms are
hackers most focused on for example if
it's cross chain is it exchange is it
defi do you know anything that people
should maybe try to avoid Yeah you
mentioned it in your answer H Julie
that's correct it cross chain CR chain
is the main one then um eum U
environment is the second one and the
third one is uh is centralized
centralized exchange as you can see
centralized exchange is for governmental
uh like very high skilled hackers um
actually cross chain also is like it's
huge money that they do on cross chain
and the main target that they had
historically in blockchain was eum of
course it started with BL with the
Bitcoin but Bitcoin very is quite secure
system but eum was less secure and they
started to be more and more secured now
but still it's still a huge part of the
revenue so cross chain eum and uh
centralized
exchange it's really funny I don't know
if you're aware but a lot of people in
crypto are annoyed with ethereum right
now because of the price now plus this
oh my
God yes I don't think it's helping yes
it's not of course there is a big part
of self-confidence we we should have for
in this area and we must know that all
those um all those like online system of
way of making money are vulnerable to
cber attacks so we must it's we must
live with it in this uh and to be just
to be sure that like to ensure our own
steps on our level if you want to like a
simple advice for example about you and
me uh I would say that the only thing
you should check if if you want to use
um a centralized exchange is just to
check their policy of refund of an
insurance policy you just have to check
if the percentage of covering insurance
policy is is covering the amount of
money you want to put on it and then you
can just sleep you can just sleep
correctly you don't care if have been
hacked by Lazarus group or by all the
world you don't care because you know
that the policy will refound you like
nothing no need to to do more than that
so I don't know are you aware if the
centralized exchange right now are
insured yeah I don't know if insurance
company would actually they are of
course of course it's part of my audit
it's part of my audit I I share that
points with with people yeah I have also
this analyze of uh how to to to to safy
safely um go into an exchange and yes
they are they have a refundable insur
policy Insurance mhm
that's interesting and it's all public
information totally public
yes jeez I should just yes uh again how
can I not know this you you you will
know it when you will do your audit with
me uh
bunny but uh also just for you to know
by bit uh after the this huge the
biggest attacks of the world on
cryptocurrency you have to know that
they could refound and they could be
available again just 72 hours after you
have to understand how huge capacity
skills it is from bybit side to totally
cover the Fone totally cover the loss
and to be able to provide never stop
withdrawal yes almost never like it took
them 18 hour to be able to put back
again the service and 72 hours to cover
all the all the Lost do you imagine 1.46
billion have been covered in 72 hours
just to show the strength of this system
of of bybit so it's just to give them
back their like some of proud for them
because it's not easy to to have the to
be like popular for being the the rich
the biggest attacks of the world but
they should be also uh Popular by being
the the most the fastest system recover
recovering system of the world also 72
hours you know I've heard people or
hackers scammers whatever you call them
using a I like deep fake to imitate your
face because you know a lot of
centralized exchange they actually use
this facial recognition
thing and I don't know if you know if AI
can actually hack that system that's
very interesting B I think that you have
you have you seen my my cyber security
conference because it seems like you all
your question are just my conference uh
I can even make you my conference again
and yes you are totally right AI has
been and is nowaday the the the first uh
reason of um the rate of attacks in
cryptocurrency and crypto ecosystem
because um we are in a period when the
number of attacks and the sophistication
level of attacks is a little higher than
the security system that is uh security
system all over the world I mean the
security system how do they work of
course the secure the system as much
much as possible but they mainly work as
we we identify an attack and we patch it
okay next attack identified patch
identifi patch but nowadays the number
of attacks are higher than before a lot
higher because of sophistication because
the AI so we are having more attacks
than defense and that's why there is so
much wave into into blockchain ecosystem
U and even more in AUM and cross chain
attacks let's say now everybody after
watching this video they're like oh my
God I need to do something about my
current situation so what they'll do is
they um remove all the extensions right
yes
and voila that's it uh for for
the web browser environment yes some
people will tell you I use a VPN is it
correct I am correct I am totally safe
if I use the VPN for for example so the
answer again is No I mean there is many
ways to find your identity again because
a VPN is just one of of the way to
change your localization but you as a
person as a computer you have many
identity on you that you don't even know
and uh the system the platform that I
will show you for for the next time if
you want uh is analyzing graphic card
signature signal it's analyzing U
motherboard
signal it's analyzing every like your
web browser signals and all that he he
creates um a hash he create a an a
unique uh number on your computer and
the fact is if you just change your IP
it's so small regarding all the rest of
identification system uh solutions that
that he can provide that it won't change
the number and you will say no you
change your VPN but I I still recognize
you because I still in the world can see
your graphic card your motherboard your
programs your web browser and you I can
identify you and this the scary thing is
that he will tell you even how many
times you came to me even if you try to
change your localization he will say you
you came here 17 time and this is 70th
time arrive to me so yeah I feel so
hopeless right now like
what even that don't work yes but that's
why I say to stay anonymous means also
not to create too much person
personality on your computer not to
personalize it too much to remain with
as uh as as simple as possible you
should I will provide you also something
else if you want empty your cookies very
often don't let cookies by bit came from
cookies just to tell you it was cookies
oh really yeah cookies on Google Chrome
okay the infected
iws uh S3 um Cloud uh from safe and then
it introduce um f like vulnerable
cookies on Google Chrome computer of
bybit owners so it came from that web
browser again you know you should just
write all these things down and then
sell it as like a course or like a
guideline people will buy it because yes
that's why now after talking to you I'm
freaking out that's why I make my audit
I put everything on my audit I when I
make my audit I I provide question to to
people they answer many many many
question and every question after that I
put a rate on it from 0 to two 0 to five
1 to five 1 to four depending on the
question and in the end of my audit you
have a full uh Excel file with many many
many many information on different
subjects and with a rate with a final
rate that is that I called um uh a score
like um a security I called it like a
security scored level and this secure
score level represent your uh your
safeness at at the point at this moment
and uh through that we can identify the
aspect of your life Digital Life that
you have to improve and then you will
see that the the you will see that the
score will raise uh day after days and
you then you will be safe if you start
to reach a score about 85% or
87% uh you will be able to to be good no
one uh as far uh today reach uh I am
very strict with people no one reach
more than 91% is the highest score but
yeah but even 100% will represent just
my vision on the best you can do on
security but my first advice is don't
think that you will be 100% secure but
if you do that you will be okay well
you've given people a lot of good
suggest questions and great insights
thank you so much thank you also buny
for for inviting me in your in your uh
YouTube if you want to check out tenum
the link below gives you 10% off all
products stay safe online